Guide to the National Religious Partnership for the Environment Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- National Religious Partnership for the Environment, 1992-2010; Series I
  - Organization and policy records
    - Correspondence
      - Filed by name or topic
        - White House: Al Gore - copies of letters sent to Gore by religious organizations in NRPE letter-writing campaign, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - White House: Office of Environmental Policy / Council on Environmental Quality, including to/from Kathleen McGinty, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Whole Earth, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - World Vision, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Program activities / staff
      - Creation Care Awards
        - Applications, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Applications, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Staff
        - Staff retreat, 2001 October (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Information gathering: state/regional programs
        - Appalachia, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 13)
          See also similar information gathered in connection with Mission to Washington event 1996-1997
        - California - list of religious leaders and organizations, no date (Box 8, Folder 14)
        - California, including Environmental Ministries, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 15)
        - Colorado, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 16)
        - Connecticut, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 17)
        - Council of Churches of the Ozarks, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 18)
        - Florida, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 19)
        - Georgia, including regarding toxic pollution in Brunswick, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 20)
        - Illinois - Bethel New Life, Chicago, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 21)
        - Maryland, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 22)
        - Mexico, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 23)
        - Michigan, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 24)
        - Minnesota, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 25)
        - Missouri, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 26)
        - New Jersey, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 27)
        - New Mexico, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 28)
        - New York, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 29)
        - Oregon - Hispanic Ministry, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 30)
        - Oregon - Ecumenical Ministries/ Interfaith Network for Earth Concerns, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 31)
        - Oregon - Portland Interfaith Network, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 32)
        - Pacific Northwest, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 33)
        - Pennsylvania, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 34)
        - Southeast U.S., 1996 (Box 8, Folder 35)
        - Tennessee, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 36)
        - Washington DC, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 37)
        - Washington state, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 38)
        - West Virginia, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Campaigns and events
    - Campaign for Sustainability and Justice
      - Launch of campaign, Washington DC, 1993 October 4 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Interdenominational hearings on environmental justice, 1994 May (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Clinton administration meeting, Washington DC, 1994 June 16 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Fellowship retreat program, 1994 November-December (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Consumption meeting, Washington DC, 1994 June (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Consumption background materials, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Consumption background materials - Harwood Group, including report "Too Much of a Good Thing", 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Consumption background materials - Merck Family Fund, including draft of address "Sustainability and the System Problem", 1994–1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Consumption background materials - University of Maryland materials, includes "Consumption, Global Stewardship, and the Good Life" conference, "Consumption, Well-Being, and Virtue" Hurst Lecture, "Ethics and Global Population" report., 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Justice and environment briefing, 1995 January 9-10 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Justice and environment briefing background materials, 1994 November (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Framework papers, 1995 January (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - NRPE day, Washington DC, 1995 March 30 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Draft papers - Overconsumption, Sustainability and Well-Being, 1995 June (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Models of engagement on environment, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Children's Environmental Health Campaign
      - Children's environmental health initiative background materials - includes "Familiaris Consortio," "Putting Children and Families First," "Children's Health and the Environment," "Environment and Children's Health.", 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Children's environmental health initiatice background materials - includes "Environmental Pollution, Neurotoxicity, and Criminal Violence.", 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - "A women's lens on foreign policy" symposium, Washington DC, International Women's Health Coalition, 1997 May 21 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Children's environmental health network background materials - includes "Children's Health and the Environment" paper, "Questions for Candidates and Elected Officials," "Facts on Environmental Health Threats to Children.", 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Children's environmental health initiative reports, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Children's environmental health initiative background materials - includes National Council of Catholic Women materials, advisory materials on grassroots movements, 2000-2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - "Faith, Environment, and the Well-Being of Children: A Call to Greater Commitment" meeting, 2002 December 10-12 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "Environmental Hazards to the Unborn Child" paper, 2003 October (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Children's environmental health meeting - includes "Women of Faith for Children's Environmental Health" executive summary, 2001 February 6 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Children's environmental health initiative background materials - includes the California Project, 2001-2003 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Children's environmental health initiative, 2005 July (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Children's environmental health - "Protecting the Health of Unborn and Young Children" meeting, 2005 July 21 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Partnership Moves Forward
      - "A gathering for the future of religion and environment" conference, 1996 May 6-9 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Mission to Washington
      - Mission to Washington leadership event, Washington DC - includes event materials and Lebanon Baptist Church landfill press clippings, 1997 February 5-6 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Mission to Washington leadership event related correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Mission to Washington leadership event conference with Al Gore, 1997 February (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Mission to Washington leadership event correspondence, Washington DC, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - "Healing and Defending God's Creation" publication, Presbyterian Church USA, no date (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Mission to Washington related press releases - St. John's Church, Elizabeth New Jersey, 1995-1998 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Mission to Washington related press releases - Eastern Loudoun Times and Loudoun Times-Mirror; the Benediction Sisters of the Sophia Center, Kansas City; Minnesota Catholic Conference, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Mission to Washington related press releases - Oakridge Tennessee; Redwood Rabbis; Pearly Gate Baptist Church, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Mission to Washington related press releases - Mount Olive Missionary Baptist Church, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Mission to Washington related press releases - Villanueva/Promised Land/Dallas/Fort Worth area, Texas; Hope Takes Root, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Mission to Washington related press releases - Temple Beth El; 46th Street Baptist church, Philadelphia, 1995-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Material from First Presbyterian Church of Kirkwood, Missouri, 1994-1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Conferences - Presbyterians for Restoring Creation conference on overpopulation; community wide environmental justice conference; Canticle of Creation newsletter, 1995 November 11-1997 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Mission to Washington related materials - Metropolitan Alliance of Congregations, Chicago, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Mission to Washington related press releases, Texas, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
        New Waverly Baptist Church; Sagemont Presbyterian Church; World Stewardship Institute; El Puente and the Community Alliance for the Environment; United Jewish Organizations
      - Mission to Washington related materials, 1997-2001 October 20 (Box 8, Folder 11)
        Orange County Interfaith Coalition for the environment, California "Caring for Creation IV" conference; Tri-City Interfaith Stewardship Initiative, Louisiana; Interfaith Center for Environmental Stewardship, Grand Island New York
    - Interfaith Climate and Energy Campaign
      Including preparatory and related materials.
      - State interfaith global warming campaign - selected press clips; documentation and press coverage, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - State interfaith global warming campaign - selected press clips, 1998-2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - State interfaith global climate change campaign reports (18 reports), 2001 September (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Religious leaders' statements on global climate change - includes progress update for W. Alton Jones Foundation from the West Virginia Council of Churches, 2000 June, 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Climate change - Iowa; Michigan, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Climate change - Oregon; Washington; West Virginia; Wisconsin, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Climate change - Ecumenical Ministries of Oregon, includes press releases, "Banking on Climate Change" paper, heavily annotated Climate Change Briefing, 1999-2001 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Climate conferences - Ohio conference press correspondence; "a Climate for the Common Good" NRPE conference; NRPE climate conference budget, 1998-1999 May 27-2000 April 11-12 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Climate change training meetings budget, 2000 September (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - National interfaith training on global warming meeting, Washington DC, 2000 September 16-18 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - "Climate Change and Energy Activity In the American Religious Community" - statements and press clips, 2001 April (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Let there be light" open letter to the President, the Congress, and the American people on energy conservation and God's creation, 2001 May (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Responses to House debate on energy policy, 2001 July (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Interfaith climate change campaign plan, 2001 September-October (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Interfaith climate change campaign training, 2002 January (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Interfaitjh climate and energy campaign Senate appeal, 2002 February (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Young leaders retreat, 2002 April (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - "Let there be light", 2002 May-November (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Cafe (corporate average fuel economy) Days, energy conservation, WWJD (What Would Jesus Drive), 2002 July (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - "What Would Jesus Drive" - includes presentation materials and Fenton Communications correspondence, 2002 Fall (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - "What Would Jesus Drive" press coverage, 2002 Fall (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Interfaith climate change network, 2002 December 4 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Fuel economy campaign press releases, first half, 2002 September-November (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Fuel economy campaign press releases, second half, 2002 September-November (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Interfaith climate and energy campaign, Detroit meeting, 2002 November 19-21 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Healthy building network, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Interfaith climate and energy campaign - state proposals, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - "What Would Jesus Drive" - includes press coverage and leader's statements, 2003 Spring (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Interfaith global climate change "What Should the Governor Drive" state reports - includes Michigan state report, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Interfaith global climate change "What Should the Governor Drive" state reports - includes correspondence, Oregon state report, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - "What Should the Governor Drive" - includes media coverage summaries, state reports, 2003 September-October (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - "What Should the Governor Drive" - includes media coverage summaries, state reports, 2003 September-October (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - "Renewing the Face of the Earth", 2004 February (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - "Renewing the Face of the Earth" - includes executive summary, proposals, and budget, 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Interfaith climate and energy campaign - clean air letter to President Bush, 2004 April (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Interfaith climate and energy campaign - includes correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Interfaith climate and energy campaign - correspondence, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Climate Senate hearing, 2004 May (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - "Earth's Climate Embraces us all" plea from religion and science for action on global climate change, 2004 July (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Interfaith global climate change - interfaith call for global climate justice, 2004 July 8 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Interfaith climate and energy campaign - state energy charters, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - "Renewing the Covenant", 2005 May 2-3 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - "God's Climate Embraces Us All", 2005-2008 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Interfaith global climate change - part one, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Interfaith global climate change - part two, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Publicity and outreach
    - NRPE brochure materials, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Memoranda to members of Board, editorial boards, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Ad in New York Times, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Philip Clapp, Environmental Strategies, re. mailings, 1995 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Press: correspondence with newspapers, articles about NRPE, partners, 1996-2003 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Op-ed pieces, including David Gelernter's "Making a Moral Case Against the Tyranny of Environmentalism: In Rats We Trust" abd responses, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - NRPE website content development (2 notebooks) (Box 15)
    - NRPE website content development, including progress reports (Box 16)
- Partner Organizations, 1990-2009; Series II
  - Coalition on the Environment and Jewish Life
    - Organization and policy records
      - Administrative materials part 1, 1990s (Box 17, Folder 1)
        Includes budgets, event materials, membership directory, invoices, applications for funding, strategic plans, memorandum, reports, initiatives, newsletters, correspondence, executive summaries, program proposals
      - Administrative materials part 2, 1990s (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Administrative materials part 3, 1990s (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - 18 month budget and programs report, 1994 December 20 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - "Action needed to help endangered species recover", 1995-1998 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Newsletters, 1996 February 10-14, 1998-2001 (Box 17, Folder 6)
        Includes "Choosing Life: Scientific and Jewish Perspectives on Biological Diversity" event material, 1998 Summer newsletter, 1999 Fall newsletter, 1999 Winter newsletter, 2001 Winter newsletter
      - Event and program materials, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 7)
        Iincludes COEJL Jewish environmental leadership training institute, Washington, DC; "A Healthy Baby Girl;" and "Jewish Group Declares Endangered Species Bill an "Ark" for Survival"
      - Press releases - includes "On the Urgency of a Jewish Response to the Environmental Crisis;" "Operation Noah", 1992 March 10; 1996 October 4 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - COEJL strategic planning retreat, 1998 October 22-23 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Reports on Tu B'Shvat, 1996 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - COEJL regional affiliates update, 2000 June (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - COEJL activities overview, 2001 (Box 18, Folder 3)
        Includes financial report, regional affiliates update, "Energy Security: A Call to Action" materials, activities report, media and direct campaign overview, letters from Jewish leaders to President Bush concerning energy crisis, correspondence, strategic plan, "Vulnerability and Adaptation to Climate Change" report
      - COEJL activities overview, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 4)
        Includes reports, correspondence, proposals regarding COEJL's future actions, schedule of revenues and expenses, Interfaith Climate and Energy Campaign events timeline, materials from regional leaders meeting in 2002 May
      - COEJL program proposal - includes correspondence between NRPE and COEJL concerning COEJL raising $200,000, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - COEJL Board of Trustees meetings - includes agendas, updates, financial reports, minutes, project reports, selected press clips, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - COEJL background materials - includes selected press clips, sample COEJL campaign documents, COEJL Board of Trustees correspondence, 2003-2007 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - COEJL background materials - includes financial reports, project descriptions, program overviews and strategic assessments, 2001–2007 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Campaigns and events
      - Ninth Rabbinic Training Institute, Towards a Jewish Philosophy of the Natural World, 1993–1994 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Headwaters Sanctuary Project, Choosing Life, 50th Anniversary of the U.N., 1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Headwaters Sanctuary Project, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Headwaters Sanctuary Project, Renewing Louisiana's Environment, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Conferences on Religions of the World and Ecology, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Leadership institutes, 1999–2000 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Report and profiles of congregational projects, 2002–2003 (Box 19, Folder 7)
        Report on the Coalition on the Environment and Jewish Life, Activity on the Climate Stewardship Act
      - Statement by Rabbi David Saperstein, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Rabbinical assembly and panel on COEJL, 1992–1999 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - Greening Synagogues project, Jewish Global Environmental Network work plan, 2004–2005 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Publicity and outreach
      - Press compilation, organizers packet, 1995–2003 (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - Operation Noah, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Biodiversity, Parshat Noah, and a Jewish Environmental Ethic, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Building a Jewish and Environmental Movement, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - To Till and to Tend, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Program materials
      - Scholarship on environmental ethics and stewardship, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Brochures and informational packets part 1, 1992–2006 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Brochures and informational packets part 2, 2005–2009 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Evangelical Environmental Network
    - Organization and Policy Records
      - Agendas, applications for funding, budgets, correspondence, memorandum, six month report, 1993–1996 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Budgets, correspondence, membership, reports, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, memorandum, 1998-2002 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, memorandum, policy statements, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, memorandum, policy statements, 2000 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, memorandum, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, membership, notes, 2001–2002 (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Budgets, correspondence, membership, memorandum, policy statements, 2003–2005 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Campaigns and events
      - Clean Car Campaign, 107th Congress, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Clean Car Campaign, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - What Would Jesus Drive?, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - What Would Jesus Drive?, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 1)
        Campaign discussion paper
      - What Would Jesus Drive?, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - What Would Jesus Drive?, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - What Would Jesus Drive?, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 4)
        Press coverage
      - What Would Jesus Drive?, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - SUV Debate, 2003 (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Creation Care Conference, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - The Evangelical Climate Initiative, 2006–2007 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Publicity and outreach
      - Media coverage, 2001–2002 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Media coverage, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Media coverage, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Program materials
      - Brochures and pamphlets, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Brochures and pamphlets, 1996–1998 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Creation-Care in Ministry manual, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Scholarship, 1990–2004 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A.
    - Organization and policy records
      - Administrative materials part 1 - includes event materials, invoices, strategic plans, memorandum, reports, initiatives, correspondence and program proposals, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Administrative materials part 2 - includes event materials, invoices, strategic plans, memorandum, reports, initiatives, correspondence, program proposals and budgets, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Administrative materials part 3 - includes event materials, invoices, strategic plans, memorandum, reports, initiatives, correspondence, program proposals and budgets, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Administrative materials part 4 - includes event materials, invoices, strategic plans, memorandum, reports, initiatives, correspondence, program proposals and membership directories, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Administrative materials part 5 - includes event materials, invoices, strategic plans, memorandum, reports, initiatives, correspondence and program proposals, 1990s (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Administrative materials part 6 - includes event materials, invoices, strategic plans, memorandum, reports, initiatives, correspondence, program proposals, budgets and membership directories, 2001–2008 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Ecumenical Anthology of Church environmental statements and policies part 1, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Ecumenical Anthology of Church environmental statements and policies part 2, 2004 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Campaigns and events
      - Black Church Economic and Environmental Justice, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Black Church Economic and Environmental Justice, 1994–1995 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Black Church Economic and Environmental Justice, 1995 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Black Church Economic and Environmental Justice, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Black Church Economic and Environmental Justice, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Black Church Economic and Environmental Justice, 1995–2001 (Box 25, Folder 5)
        Notes
      - Earth Day, 1994–2004 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - God's Earth Our Home - worship resources, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 6a)
      - Climate Change, 1998–1999 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Climate Change, 2001–2002 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Orthodox Church Summit, 1991–1995 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Orthodox Church Summit, 1997 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - God's Mandate, 2005 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Southwest Organizing Project, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Interfaith Coalition on Energy and Interfaith Global Warming campaigns, God's Care for Creation: Symposium III, 1900s (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Global warming conferences, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Web of Creation, Commission for Racial Justice, Endangered Species Act and the Environmental Justice Covenant Congregation Program, 1990–1999 (Box 26, Folder 8)